Guide to the Richard C. Jeffrey Papers, 1934-2002 ASP.2003.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Richard C. Jeffrey Papers
1934-2002
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jeffrey, Richard C.
ASP.2003.02
16 Linear Feet (33 boxes)
Richard Jeffrey, an American philosopher, logician, and probability theorist, represents one of the most influential philosophers working in decision theory. He was also a major advocate of developing and securing the heritage of logical empiricism, himself championing 'radical probabilism', a view that denies objective probability and abandons attempts to analyze judgment into a rational and an empirical component. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
Richard Jeffrey is considered to be one of the most influential philosophers of decision-making in the 20th century. His work is unified by his development of Bayesianism, the view that making up one's mind is a matter of adopting judgmental probabilities. Likewise, he advocated radical probabilism by denying objective probability and abandoning attempts to analyze judgment into a rational and an empirical component.
Jeffrey was born in 1926 in Boston, Massachusetts. He earned his M.A. in Philosophy at the University of Chicago in 1952 and his Ph.D. at Princeton University in 1957. After holding academic positions at City College of New York, Stanford University, and the University of Pennsylvania, he joined the faculty of Princeton University in 1974 and became a professor emeritus there in 1999. He was also a visiting professor at the University of California, Irvine.
His philosophical career is closely connected to the story of 20th century philosophy, and most of his teachers had participated in the development of Logical Positivism in Vienna and Berlin in the twenties and early thirties. He collaborated with Rudolf Carnap at Chicago, with Kurt Gödel at the Institute for Advanced Study, and with Carl Gustav Hempel at Princeton.
Among his many publications are such works as The Logic of Decision (McGraw Hill 1965), a collection of essays entitled Probability and the Art of Judgment (Cambridge 1992), and also two textbooks entitled Formal Logic: Its Scope and Limits (McGraw Hill, first edition 1967) and Computability and Logic, with G. Boolos (first published in 1974).
Richard Jeffrey passed away on November 9, 2002.
Scope and Content Notes
The Jeffrey Papers include biographical material, correspondence, research and lecture notes, teaching documents, and drafts of published and unpublished writings by Jeffrey and others. Series I comprises biographical information. Included in the correspondence series (Series II) are extensive exchanges with Jeffrey's close colleagues, teachers, friends, and collaborators such as Rudolf Carnap, Carl Gustav Hempel, and Brian Skyrms. Materials in the research series (Series III) range from sketchy outlines, typescripts and documents reflecting Jeffrey's collaborations with Carnap, to numerous grant proposals and projects that are indicative of Jeffrey's research interests at the time. Series IV focuses on Jeffrey's writings and publications including manuscript drafts, lecture notes, and his editorial work, which centers mainly on the publication of Hempel's Selected Philosophical Essays. Series V covers material from Jeffrey's teaching activities, such as syllabi, teaching notes, reading lists, and exams. Series VI contains writings by others in form of unpublished drafts or annotated published pieces.
Arrangement
Below is an overview of the general series structure. Detailed scope and content notes are available at the series and subseries level:
Series I. Biographical Material
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Research
Series IV. Writings, Lectures, and Publications
Series V. Teaching
Series VI. Writings by Others
Please note that typescripts that were originally enclosed with correspondence usually stayed with the correspondence. Published articles were removed and, if annotated, filed under the author's last name in the series "Writings by Others." We therefore advise users to look under the author's name in both the correspondence and the writings series when trying to locate an article.
Access Restrictions
Access to the collection is open for research with the following exceptions: Letters of recommendation and some individual files in the general correspondence series are closed. Access to material in the teaching series and to some files in the correspondence series is restricted; requests are subject to individual review by curator. Please contact the Archives of Scientific Philosophy for additional information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edith Jeffrey on August 6, 2003.
Previous Citation
Richard C. Jeffrey Papers, 1934-2002, ASP.2003.02, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.
Related Material
Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1899-1970, ASP.1974.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Archives & Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Carl Gustav Hempel Papers, 1903-1997, ASP.1999.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Archives & Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Bruno de Finetti Papers, 1924-2000, ASP.1992.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Archives & Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Personal correspondence; Probabilities; Judgment; Bayesian statistical decision theory; Logic; Logical positivism; Logic, Symbolic and mathematical; Statistical decision; Decision-making; Induction (Logic); Science -- Statistical methods; Mathematical statistics; Empiricism; Philosophy; Causality (Physics); Offprints; Manuscripts for publication; Lecture notes; Princeton University -- Faculty; De Finetti, Bruno; Jeffrey, Richard C.; Skyrms, Brian; Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav); Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970
- Biographical Material, 1998-2003; I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series provides biographical information on Jeffrey, including an interview on DVD conducted at his home shortly before his death, and commemorative documents.
  - Curricula Vitae and Bibliographies, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Jeffrey on Game Theory/Decision Theory, Princeton, [on DVD], August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commemorative Documents: Memorial Booklet, Memorial Resolution, and Obituaries, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jeffrey's Grades at Boston University and University of Chicago [CLOSED], 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence A-Z, 1947-2002; II.
  This series contains Jeffrey's correspondence with individuals and institutions. The files of this series are arranged alphabetically according to the names of individuals, institutions, events, or subject matters. This arrangement is an expansion of Jeffrey's existing filing system; new files were added and existing files at times expanded when related and previously unorganized documents were found.
  - A, 1983-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Albert, Jeffrey M.: see "Cost-Benefits Analysis" in series 'Writings by Others." (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic (ASL) Nominating Committee, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - B, 1964-2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bar-Hillel, Maya, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bartley, W. W. [CLOSED], 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baumer, William H. [CLOSED], 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Benacerraf, Paul [CLOSED], 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bolker, Ethan, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Boyer, David L. ("Jeffie"), 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Broome, John, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Butrick [CLOSED], 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - C, 1964-2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cambridge University Press [CLOSED], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cargile, James, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chellas, Brian [CLOSED], 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - City College of New York [CLOSED], 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Costantini, Domenico, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - D, 1966-2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Davidson, Donald: Festschrift, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - de Finetti, Bruno, 1969-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Diaconis, Persi, 1973-2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dorling, Jon, 1982-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - E, 1965-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Essler, Wilhelm/Erkenntnis, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - F, 1964-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ferreira, Fernando, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Frye, Marilyn [CLOSED], 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - G, 1963-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gaifman, Haim, 1964-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Galavotti, Maria Carla, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Garber, Daniel [CLOSED], 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Geach, Peter T., 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Goldman, Alvin I., 2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - H, 1962-2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hempel, Carl Gustav, 1934-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hild, Mathias [CLOSED], 1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Howson, Colin [CLOSED], 1993-2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Humburg, Jürgen, 1963-1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Institute on Religion in an Age of Science, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Institute Vienna Circle/International Centre for Economic Research (ICER), 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - J, 1993-2002 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Journal of Symbolic Logic/Alonzo Church, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - K, 1948-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kemeny, John: "Asymptotic Expansion", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kyburg, Henry E. [CLOSED], 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - L, 1964-2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Lambert, Joseph Karl [CLOSED], 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Lehrer, Keith, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lewis, David K.: "Conventions of Language", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - M, 1964-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Matthews, Robert A.J., 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - MCA Music: Permission to Publish Request, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - McGee, Vann, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1961-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - N, 1947-2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - O, 1964-2002 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - P, 1956-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania, University of, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy of Science Journal: Referee Report and Articles (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy of Science Association (PSA), 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Popper, Karl, 1960-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Putnam: On Schilpp Article, Letter to Carnap and Notes, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Q, 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - R, 1967-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ramsey, Frank Plumpton, 1978-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Richter, Reed: Papers and Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Risse, Mathias: Papers and Correspondence, 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Roorda, J. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - S, 1964-2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Salmon, Wesley: APA Paper "Carnap's Inductive Logic" & Comments by Jeffrey and Kemeny, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Savage, Jimmie, 1960-1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Segerberg, Krister [CLOSED], undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Selinger [CLOSED], undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Shimony, Abner, 1965-2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Smokler, Howard E. [CLOSED], 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Solomon, Robert [CLOSED], 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spielman, Steve, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Spohn, Wolfgang [CLOSED], 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stalnaker, Robert, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University [CLOSED], 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Stöltzner, Michael, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - T, 1967-1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Teller, Paul [CLOSED], 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - U, 1975-1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1969-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - V, 1956-1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Van Fraassen, Bas: Papers and Correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Velleman, David: Dissertation Report [CLOSED], undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - W, 1965-2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Wagner, Carl, 1989-2002 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Weirich, Paul [CLOSED], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - X,Y,Z, 1970-2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Zabell, Sandy [CLOSED], 1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Zabludowski, Andrzej [CLOSED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Zynda, Lyle: Dissertation Report [CLOSED], undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Research, 1952-1997; III.
  This series is divided into three subseries. The first subseries comprises Jeffrey's general research notes. The second subseries focuses on Jeffrey's collaboration with Carnap, largely in the form of correspondence and exchanges of drafts. The third subseries contains Jeffrey's grant applications, awards, and summary reports on concluded projects.
  - Research Notes, 1959-1997; 1.
    Jeffrey's research material consists mostly of handwritten and typed documents recording his reflections on subjective probability, decision theory, Bayesianism and related topics, including comments about the works of others. Also featured is a notebook on the Richard Lewontin Lectures that Jeffrey attended while in Harvard in the Fall of 1984.
    The files are arranged in chronological order starting with the earliest; undated material is placed at the end of the series in alphabetical order according to folder title.
    - Weather Forecasting: Readings, 1906-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Notes on Linear Difference Equations, Probability, and Linear Programming, 1959 and undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Early Drafts and Notes, Some in Form of Correspondence with David Miller and Richard Braithwaite, 1964-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Early Drafts and Notes, Some in Form of Correspondence with David Miller and Richard Braithwaite, 1964-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3 B)
    - Notes on the Interpretation of Modal and Intuitionistic Logic, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kinematics: Good's Ploy, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - London Notes, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Cost-Benefit Analysis: Papers and Readings, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Cost-Benefit Analysis: Papers and Readings, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7 B)
    - Probabilistic Thinking, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Why I Am Still a (Born-Again) Bayesian, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Notes and Correspondence with Sarah Lichtenstein on 'Calibration', 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Notes and Correspondence with Sarah Lichtenstein on 'Calibration', 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10 B)
    - Ratifiability (Corrected), 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - When Is It Best to Accept Free Information Before Deciding?, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Richard Lewontin Lectures: Notes, Harvard Fall 1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Subjective Chance, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Paradox Lost & Bayesian Methodology, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Carnap, Bayesianism in the '90s, Berlin Talk 'Probability Logic', and Related, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Matter of Fact and Conditionals, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Matter of Fact and Conditionals, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 17 B)
    - Chance Kinematics (e.g. Prisoners' Dilemmas for Clones), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Kenji's Matrix. Letter to Charles, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Son of Born: Judgemental Probabilities in Quantum Mechanics, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - The Shooting Room, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Wagner, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "Two Envelope Problem" (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Abner and Earman on Jaynes (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Assigning Probabilities to Open and Closed Formulas (Fenstad) (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Bell's Inequalities, Holt, Clauser, et. al. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Conditional Expected Utility as a Measure of Choiceworthiness (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Conditioning (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Constructing Reliable Indicators out of Unreliable Ones: An Example (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Craig-Heth: An Example (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Data are Stable Aspects of Probability Distinctions" (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Determinism and Free Will (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Equivalent Random Variables (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Exchangeability: De Finetti's Representation Theorem (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Full & Partial Exchangeability (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - The Green Bean: Notes on Probability (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Historical Remarks on Coherence (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Huygens, Christiaan: Oevre completès, Vol. 14, Annotated Copy and Research Notes (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - The Latest Thinking on the Problem of Old Evidence (New Explanation) (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Laws of Large Numbers (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Loomis, Villegas, Dubins (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - M.C.'s Book (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - A Message From the Old Guru (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - 'Mini-Aumann Theorem' (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - 'Mini-Aumann Theorem' (Box 7, Folder 44 B)
    - Nash's Solution to the Bargaining Problem (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Noncommutative Updating at the Circus & Kullback in Discrete Terms (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Notebook with Research Notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Notes on "Abner, Domenico, Dawid,..." et. al (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 'N. Probabilities' (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Order of Discovery~Order of Learning (Janina): Epistemology without the Given (◊Jim, 1957): A Study in Radical Physicalism (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Probabilistic Epistemology (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Probability and Confirmation (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Probable Misdiagnosis by Reliable Tests (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Quest for Uncertainty (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - A Reinterpretation of de Finetti's Work in Terms of Carnap's Two Concepts of Probability (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Relevant Evidence (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Religious Belief & Scientific Knowledge (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - RCJ's Replacement of Ramsey (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sex Bias at Berkeley? (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Skyrm's Version of Causal Decision Theory (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - A Standard Form for EFS's (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Theory of Automata (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Research Notes (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Utilities, Interpersonal Preference, and Aggregation (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - What the Histopathologist Saw (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - What Time Does the Next Owl Leave? (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Carnap Material, 1952-1991; 2.
    Carnap and Jeffrey had been close friends and collaborators since Jeffrey studied and received his Master's Degree under Carnap at the University of Chicago. The documents in this subseries reflect this close personal and professional relationship, mainly in form of correspondence with Carnap and his wife Ina, as well as exchanges of drafts and research notes. Carnap often included Jeffrey in his exchanges with other individuals, therefore numerous letters are carbon copies of Carnap's correspondence with others. Also featured are writings on Carnap authored by Jeffrey and others.
    The folders are arranged in chronological order, followed by undated material.
    - Carnapiana: Drafts, Notes Correspondence with or on Carnap, 1952-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Carnapiana: Drafts, Notes Correspondence with or on Carnap, 1952-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1 B)
    - Copies of Correspondence with Carnap regarding Jeffrey's PhD Thesis, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Copies of Revised and Edited Drafts of Carnap's Schilpp Autobiography, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Copies of Revised and Edited Drafts of Carnap's Schilpp Autobiography, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Copies of Revised and Edited Drafts of Carnap's Schilpp Autobiography, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Copies of Revised and Edited Drafts of Carnap's Schilpp Autobiography, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Carnap's Comments on Jeffrey's Ms. "On Changing One's Betting Function" and Handwritten Notes by Carnap and Jeffrey, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Carnap Correspondence, 1958-1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Carnap Correspondence, 1958-1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Carnap's Comments on Jeffrey Manuscripts and Letters by Jeffrey, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Goodman's Query: Letter by Jeffrey to Carnap, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Jeffrey-Carnap Collaboration, Drafts and Notes, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Jeffrey-Carnap Collaboration, Drafts and Notes, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 12 B)
    - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Jeffrey-Carnap Collaboration, Drafts and Notes, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Jeffrey-Carnap Collaboration, Drafts and Notes, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Jeffrey-Carnap Collaboration, Drafts and Notes, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 14 B)
    - Letter by Carnap to Haim Gaifman, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Translation and Publication of Carnap's Early Essays: Correspondence with Cambridge University Press and Hanna Carnap-Thost/Arthur Benson, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Jeffrey-Carnap Correspondence: Editing Project with Open Court, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Carnap Material Used for Teaching: Typescripts "On Protocol Sentences" and Translation of Carnap's "'ber Protokolls'tze", undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Carnap and His Friends: The Career of Logical Positivism", Phil 531 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Copies of Carnap Articles "Über Protokollsätze", and "Truth and Confirmation" (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Grant Proposals and Projects, 1960-1993; 3.
    This series contains Jeffrey's grant applications, project reports, and related correspondence and paperwork. Included is a project proposal by Hempel and a grant evaluation by Jeffrey of a proposal by Max Black.
    - NSF Project Proposals, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - AFOSR (Air Force Office of Scientific Research) Grants & Contracts, 1960-1967 (Box 10, Folder 05-06)
    - ACLS Research Proposal: Logical Foundations of Bayesian Decision Theory, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - NSF Project Proposal "Collaborative Research on Bayesian Theory", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - NSF Project Proposal: Objective & Intersubjective Considerations in Decision Theory, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - NSF Project Proposal & Report: Objective & Intersubjective Considerations in Decision Theory, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - NSF Panel, 1968-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Guggenheim Proposal: Logical Foundations of Bayesian Decision Theory, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - NSF Project Proposal: Extensions of a Theory of Preference under Uncertainty, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - NSF Project Proposal "Carnap's Inductive Logic", 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - NSF Jeffrey's Evaluation of Project Proposal by Max Black, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - NEH Grant, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - NSF Project Proposal "Causality & Decision", 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
    - NSF Grant Proposal by C.G. Hempel, "Problems of Empiricism: Analytic and Pragmatist Perspectives", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - NSF Project Proposal "Probabilistic Epistemology", 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - NSF Project Proposal "Bruno de Finetti's 'Probabilismo'", 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - NSF Project Proposal, "Medical Probabilism; an Investigation of Expert Human Systems", 1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - NSF Project Proposal, "Probabilizing Pathology, an Investigation of Expert Human Systems", 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Probabilizing Pathology, Summary of Completed Project, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - NSF Grant Award for "Collaborative Research on Probability Conditionals", 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - NSF Project Proposal, "Constructivism after Carnap (Revised)", 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 08-09)
- Writings, Lectures, and Publications, 1952-2002; IV.